CHRISTOPHER CAVINESS

Redmond, WA 98052

Phone: (206) 816-2123 | Email: chriscaviness3D@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/chris-caviness/ | Portfolio: artstation.com/cavi_3d

SUMMARY

Proven multiple time leader with a desire for clear definitive working expectations and project policy. 3D artist with nearly a decade of experience using industry standard 3D applications with previous roles in both games and advertising. Dedicated to constant learning of new tools and applications.

EXPERIENCE

3D R&D Team Lead - Amazon 2021-2022 Seattle WA

- Lead a team of 3D artists through experimental workflows creating imagery of various products for use on Amazon websites and advertisements.
- Worked closely with Technical Program Managers, Engineers, and Data Scientists to determine experiment project scope and deliverables.
- Trained internal artists on upcoming project policies and new proprietary tools, and international production teams on successful projects.

Key Accomplishments:

- Accomplished our team goal of creating 2,500 3D models each within a two hour time period.
- Recreated project policy documentation for ease of use across multiple teams, leading to a reduction in submitted errors and faster task time.
- Created itemized onboarding instructions allowing for additional production teams to onboard new artists or ramp up into ongoing experimental workflows.

Senior 3D QA - Zillow 2020-2021 Seattle WA

- Created user facing floor plans using 3D scan imagery and proprietary shape tools.
- Performed quality assurance for 3D imagery collection and asset creation.
- Performed regular testing of tool updates and bug tracking.

Key Accomplishments:

- Assisted in training multiple new hire waves taking the team from 15 to 120 active annotators.
- Assisted in establishing an error repository for multiple aspects of the process for annotators to refer to before submitting final products.

Technical Program Lead - Lyft 2019-2020 Bellevue WA

- Created and presented project training materials and project policy standards across multiple teams based on the requested data needs of customers.
- Supported team leads and operators with clarifying policy questions and edge cases.
- Consulted Program Managers regarding the scalability of production work for new offices internationally.

Key Accomplishments:

- Remastered all training materials or multiple teams focusing on new operator accessibility and understanding.
- Led office wide cross training efforts between teams for anticipated international ramping.
- Successfully trained a new international office on all ongoing project policies and materials leading to full production.

3D Environment Artist - Gamma Minus UG 2016-2019 Seattle WA

- Created realistic 3D models and textures for use in Unreal Engine 4.
- Created playable levels by organizing 3D assets inside Unreal Engine...
- Collaborated with team members internationally regarding art direction and various support issues.

Key Accomplishments:

- Created a full subway station environment used as a playable level and for promotional material on the company website and Steam.
- Led the organization of level layouts.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development: University of Washington 2022 Seattle, WA

A 24-week intensive certificate program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js and ReactJS.

Bachelors of Fine Arts: Sanford-Brown College 2013-2016 Tukwila, WA

A 3-year accelerated bachelors degree program focused on gaining technical artistic skills with industry standard video game production tools and pipelines with 3D asset creation, level design, and highly collaborative team projects.

Awards:

- Graduated magna cum laude: 3.80 GPA.
- 10-time Presiden' List recipient (Maintained 4.0 GPA per guarter).
- 4-time Dean's List recipient (Maintained 3.80 GPA or higher per quarter).

SKILLS

TRANSFERABLE SKILLS:

- Team Leadership
- Technical Writing
- Teaching / Employee Training
- Presentations / Public Speaking
- Critical Thinking / Problem Solving
- Microsoft Word / Excel / PowerPoint

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- 3D Modeling (Maya / ZBrush)
- Level Design (Unreal Engine / Unity Engine)
- Adobe Photoshop / Premiere / Substance
- Sound Design
- Storyboarding
- Programming (HTML / CSS / JavaScript)